オイラが殺すはずだった
大蛇丸をやりやがった➡
Sasuke Uchiha...
I can't forgive him
'cuz he killed Orochimaru,
うちはサスケを許せねえ！
whom I planned to kill!
《喝！》
Ha!
いい目で睨みやがってるぜ トビ！
Tobi, look how he's glaring at us!
Clash!
(サスケ)うちはイタチは どこだ？
Where's Itachi Uchiha?
(デイダラ)は？
Huh?
言えば見逃してやる。
Tell me, and I'll let you go.
(デイダラ)写輪眼か…。
やっぱりコイツ イタチの弟だぜ。
Sharingan...eh?
He really is Itachi's little brother.
大蛇丸をやれたのも うちはの血の
おかげってわけだ… うん。
You were only able to kill Orochimaru
thanks to your Uchiha blood.
血統に恵まれただけの
勘違い野郎が！
You're nothing but a fool
blessed with good genes!
《速い！》
(トビ)え？
He's fast!
Huh?!
まずは１匹。
One down.
よくしゃべるお前には
イタチのことを…。
So I'll ask you,
the one with the big mouth, about Itachi.
何やってんだ トビ！
ガキだからって気抜くなよ。 うん！
What're you doing, Tobi?!
Don't let your guard down
just because he's a kid!
瞬身の術が速すぎて
ボクらじゃムリっすよ～。
His Teleportation Jutsu is too quick.
We're no match for him!
《コイツ！》
That guy...!
ヘッ！
《まずは チャクラレベルＣ１で
動きを見てやる》
First, I'll watch his movements
with chakra level C1.
Tobi! Stay back!
トビ！ 下がってろ!!
わぁ！ うわ～！
うわぁ～！
せせ… 先輩 タイム！
S-Senpai! Time out!
喝は やっちゃダメ！
チッ！
Don't do it!
先輩 後ろ後ろ！
Senpai! Behind you, behind you!
喝！
Ha!
先輩！
Senpai!
あぁ…。
厳しい先輩だったけど
いい先輩だったなぁ。
He was strict, but a good partner...
ボクは決して デイダラ先輩のことを…。
I shall never forget about you,
Deidara Senpai--!
ギャーギャーうるせえぞ！
え？
Will you shut up?!
あ～ 生きてた。
Oh, you're alive?
《掌から爆発物を作る能力か…》
The ability to produce
an explosive with his palm, huh?
《爆風で どうにか逃げ切れた。
I somehow managed to escape
by hiding in the bomb blast...
Good thing I kept
the chakra level at C1.
練り込んだチャクラをＣ１にしといて
助かったぜ… うん》
《確かに動きは速いが
コイツはどうだ？》
He definitely moves swiftly...
How about this then?
もうちょっと遊んでやるぜ。
うん！
I'll play with you a bit more!
子供だましか？
Child's play?
くだらん。
So stupid.
ハハハハ！ まだまだ!!
It's not over yet!
ハハッ！ ハハハハ！
そろそろ… いくか。
I guess...it's about time.
ウソ!?
あ？
No way!
Huh?
だよね～。
おい！
Yeah, I thought so.
Hey...!
どうだ！
あら～。
How's that?!
Oh...
やっぱ たいしたことねえな うん。
He's not much, after all...
やっぱり！
I knew it!
Hey, Tobi!
おい トビ！
テメエは どっちの味方なんだよ！
Whose side are you on anyway?!
《デイダラ : 変わり身の術か…。
A Substitution Jutsu, eh?
確かに 結構やりやがるな。
Well, he's definitely quite skilled...
Then this calls for C2.
なら ここは Ｃ２がベスト》
あっ！ そ そ… それは！
Th-That's...!
出た～！
先輩の十八番芸術のひとつ➡
Ta-daa! One of Senpai's signature
art pieces, the C2 Dragon!
Ｃ２ドラゴン！
わかってんな？ トビ！
Tobi, you know what to do, right?!
もちろんっすよ 先輩！
アレですね？
Of course, Senpai!
We're going with "that," right?!
そうだ！
その アレでいくぞ うん！
Yeah! "That" is the plan...
《あのでかいのも
爆発物になりえるのか？》
That huge thing becomes
an explosive too?
任せたぞ トビ！
オッス！
I'm counting on you, Tobi!
Right!
《しかも あの形状からして➡
And judging from its looks,
it'll be attacking from the sky...!
空からか… 厄介だ》
This is bad.
来た～！
Here he comes!
Let's show him, Senpai...
先輩のポップアートの力
見せつけてやりましょうよ！
The power of your pop art!
ポップは死んだ！ オイラのは…。
Pop art is dead! My art is...
Superflat!
スーパーフラットだ！
Ha!
喝！
《さっきとは違う… 誘導弾か》
It's different from before...
A guided missile?
《もう一人が いない。
Where's the other one?
Guess I'll start off with him!
とりあえずは アイツか！》
《フンッ 伸ばせる限界は
５メートルってとこか》
Looks like it can only reach up
to five meters, eh?
Tsk... He figured out my limit.
《チッ… 間合いを見切られたか》
That's Kakashi's trick right?!
カカシのだろ？ それ。
I'll give you credit for the skill in
changing chakra form to extend and throw.
伸ばしたり 投げたりって
形状変化は 認めてやるがよ。
コイツは さっきのとは
威力が違うぜ。
But the force of this one's different
from earlier.
Blow to bits!
吹き飛べ！
He really is swift.
《さすがに速いな。
Got him!
かかった！》
やったか。
Did I get him...?
《デイダラ : あれは… 大蛇丸の呪印か。
That's...Orochimaru's Curse Mark!
翼まで生えるとはな。
He can even grow wings?
He managed to dodge it
by flying upwards...
上手く 上へ飛んで かわしたか》
Senpai! All the land mine clay is set
and ready to go!
先輩！ 地雷粘土
すべて セッティング オーケーッス！
(デイダラ)よくやった トビ！
お前は 離れてろ！
Good job, Tobi! You stay back.
オッス！
Yessir!
《上からは 誘導弾
下からは 地雷か》
Guided missile attacks from above,
and land mines from the ground!
Ｃ２は 地雷の足止めと
空中からの ピンポイント攻撃。
The key element of
the C2 coordinated assault
is using the land mines
to slow you down
and finishing you off with
a pinpoint missile attack.
この連係攻撃が ミソだ。
Land mines are planted all around you!
お前の足元には すでに
ビッシリ地雷が 敷き詰めてある。
踏みつけただけで 自動爆破だ。
Step on one and you'll set them off!
《誘導弾を 確実に当てるためか。
He plans to ram the guided missile
right into me.
オレの攻撃範囲の外を➡
And it's flying just outside
my attack perimeter...
ギリギリまで 近づいて飛んでやがる》
その 負傷した足で➡
With that wounded leg,
オレの 空中からの攻撃を
上手くかわせるかな？ うん。
I wonder if you can dodge
my aerial attack...hmm?
The next one's gonna be big!
次のは でかいぜ！ うん！
飛ばせるか！
As if I'll let you fly away!
喝！
Ha!
ハハッ 翼でガードなんかすっから➡
That's what you get for trying to
guard yourself with wings.
もう 飛べねえな 片翼じゃあよ。
ハハハ！
You can't fly anymore, can you?
Not with one wing...
さすが デイダラ先輩！
You're awesome, Deidara Senpai!
これで 終わりにしてやるぜ！
うん！
Well, let's settle this!
そんなもんが 当たるか！
As if that'll hit me!
《ヘヘッ 足場なし。
No foothold! Fall on a land mine
and you'll lose a limb for sure!
地雷原に落ちたら
どこかは もげるぜ 確実にな》
A-A foothold?!
《あ 足場!?》
《なに!? 届いただと!?》
What?!
He reached me?
バランスが！
Deidara's balance...!
He purposely stuck his sword
in the ground?
《コイツ 刀を わざと地面に!?
地雷の有無を確かめ
足場を作った。
He tested for the presence of land mines
and created a foothold?!
足場にした 刀の長さの分➡
The length of the sword,
which he used as a foothold...
それに 片翼を使ったジャンプ。
And that jump using his single wing...
こ この位置…！
This position?!
I see. With that attack,
he lured me directly above the sword...
そうか あの攻撃で 刀の真上に
オイラを誘い込み…》
The shortest distance that
a chakra sword would reach...
《チャクラ刀の届く 最短距離を…》
うわぁ！
先輩！
Senpai!
《クッ！ 動けねえ！》
I can't move...!
This is bad!
Below me are the land mines...!
《ヤバイ… 下には 地雷が！》
うわぁっ！
Senpai!!
先輩！
やっぱ最後は爆死じゃないっすか。
テイダラ先輩のバカ野郎！
You did die by bombing, after all!
Deidara Senpai...you fool!
I keep telling you to shut up, Tobi!
ギャーギャーうるせえって
言ってんだ。 トビ。
Huh? Y-You're still alive...?
ま まだ生きてた。
しぶとい。
What a stubborn...
((ああっ！
(うっ))
この… クソガキが！
You...stupid brat!
《あの眼。 あの眼だ》
Those eyes...
It's those same eyes...
《デイダラ : チクショウ！》
Damn it!
((暁だ？ 知るか そんなもん。
"Akatsuki"?
Like I care! Don't interfere with
my appreciation of art.
オイラのアート鑑賞を
ジャマするんじゃねえ。
(サソリ)こんなガキを オレの連れに
しなきゃなんねえのか。
And I'm supposed to take
this kid as my partner...?
威勢はいいが コイツは
早死にするタイプだぜ。
He's feisty, but looks like
the type to die young.
(イタチ)リーダーの命令だ。
コイツの能力は役に立つ。
It's our leader's orders...
We can use his powers.
オイラの能力を知ってんのか？
お前ら いったい？
You know about my power?
Just who the hell are...?
(鬼鮫)近隣諸国で
反国家分子どもに加担して➡
You're the bomb terrorist
who's been supporting
the anti-government factions
in various lands.
爆破テロを起こしているのは
あなたですね。
抜け忍のあなたが
何の目的でそんなことを？
What purpose would that serve
a rogue ninja like you...?
Purpose? I have no purpose!
目的？
そんなもんありゃしねえよ。
オイラは依頼を受けて
爆発を起こすだけだ。
I get requests to set off explosions,
so I do.
オイラの作品でな。
With my creations!
作品？
そうだ。
Creations?
That's right.
見ろ。 どうだ。
Look!
Well? Such refined lines,
この洗練されたラインに
二次元的なデフォルメを追求した造形。
and a form that pursues
two-dimensional deform.
まさにアートだ。
This  is art!
But that's not all there is to my art!
だが オイラのアートは
これだけじゃない。
オイラの作品は流動的だ。
My creations flow!
When it has shape,
it's simply molded clay!
形あるときは
ただの造形物にすぎない。 うん。
これは爆発する。
But this explodes!
And the explosion causes sublimation,
その爆発により
その存在を昇華させて➡
and for the first time,
the essence of my creation appears!
初めて本来の作品になる。
That instant of sublimation is
when I experience true art!
オイラはその一瞬の昇華にこそ
アートを感じてならない。 うん。
芸術は爆発なのだ！
Art is an explosion!
うざいな。
終わりですか？
How annoying...
Is he done?
さあな。
Who knows...
Never mind... I'll do it.
もういい。 オレがやろう。
《なんだ あの目？》
What's with his eyes...?
やろうってのか!?
You wanna fight?
オレが勝ったら
お前は暁に入ってもらう。
If I win,
you will become a member of Akatsuki.
オイラを… アートをナメんじゃねえぞ！
Don't belittle...me...or my art!
オレの忍術は
何よりも崇高な芸術だ。 うん！
My ninjutsu is nothing
but noble, refined art!
アートを感じろ！
Feel my art!
喝！
Ha!
ヘヘッ！ いきがってたわりには
その程度かよ。
You talked big...
but is that all you have?
終わりだ。 うん！
It's over!
よく自分の姿を見たほうがいい。
You should take a good look
at yourself.
え？
Huh?
な… なに!?
Wh-What?!
(鬼鮫)危なかったですね。
That was close.
もう少しで
自爆するところでしたよ。
A little later and
you would've blown yourself up.
(サソリ)やっぱり
早死にするタイプだな コイツは。
I told you he was the type to die young.
幻術か！ いつの間に？
A Genjutsu! When?!
初めからですよ。
From the very beginning.
イタチさんの写輪眼を見たとき
すでに あなたは幻術の中。
From the moment you looked
in
《デイダラ : 美しい…》
《デイダラ : これは 芸術だ…》
《チッ… オイラが他人の能力に
見入っちまうなんて。
あれが芸術だと？
いや認めねえ… 認めねえぞ！》
お前の負けだ。
《ふざけるな…
オイラのほうが上だ！》
《オイラの能力は完璧だ。
誰にも負けない芸術だ！》
《オイラのほうが上だ！
負けるはずがねえ！》
(デイダラ)あんな…。
あんな!!
あ！ 起爆粘土を自分の口で
食ってるってことは…。
とっておきだ！ 次で殺す！
トビ 逃げてろ！
うわ ヤベー！ Ｃ４カルラだ！
急げ～！
《イタチを殺すための とっておきの
術だったんだがな… うん》
なに!?
(マカロフ)
これまでの 『FAIRY TAIL』は…。
(ミラジェーン)子供の頃から
ナツと仲のよかったリサーナは➡
ある事件の際に
死んだと思われていたの。
私たちは
その悲しみを乗り越えて➡
なんとか歩き出した。
(ナツ)で エドラスで
リサーナと再会したわけだ。
しかも
こっちのリサーナだったんだよな。